Marcos Tirador Curriculum Vitae

CONTACT INFORMATION

Full name: Marcos Manuel Tirador Del Riego Email address: marcosmath44@gmail.com

Website: marcostirador.github.io

I am an instructor of Data Structures and Algorithms in the Computer Science program at the University of Havana. I recently graduated with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Havana, supervised by Dr. Felix Gotti and Dr. Luis Ramiro Piñeiro. I am currently working on my application to graduate school. During the past 4 years, I have been conducting research in factorization theory under the supervision of Dr. Felix Gotti, with a focus on the atomic structure of commutative rings and monoids. I also have a keen interest in theoretical computer science, particularly in areas such as cryptography and complexity theory.

EDUCATION

Degree	September 2019 — January 2024 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Top of the class, graduated of honors, outstanding in research and academics, acknowledged as the second most impactful researcher among the graduating students of the university.	
University	University of Havana Havana, Cuba	
Degree	September 2015 — May 2018 High School Diploma Vocational Pre-University Insitute of Exact Sciences Vladimir I. Lenin Havana, Cuba	

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

(1) On the set of molecules of numerical and Puiseux monoids (with Marly Gotti)

In: Rings, Monoids and Module Theory, Springer Proceedings in Mathematics & Statistics book series (Eds. A. Badawi and J. Coykendall). Springer, Singapore. Vol. 382 (2022) 111–125, doi:10.1007/978-981-16-8422-7-5.

- (2) Factorization in additive monoids of evaluation polynomial semirings (with K. Ajran, J. Bringas, Bangzheng Li & E. Singer)
 Communications in Algebra, Vol. 51:10 (2023) 4347-4362, doi:10.1080/00927872.2023.2208672.
- (3) Subatomicity in Rank-2 Lattice Monoids (with C. Liu & P. Rodriguez)
 Journal of Commutative Algebra 16(3): 337-352 (Fall 2024), doi: 10.1216/jca.2024.16.337.

Marcos Tirador Curriculum Vitae

(4) On the atomicity of power monoids of Puiseux monoids (with V. Gonzalez, E. Li, H. Rabinovitz & P. Rodriguez)
International Journal of Algebra and Computation (to appear), doi: 10.1142/S0218196724500565.

Awards

2024	World Finalist at the International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)
2022	Bronze Medal at the XXV Iberoamerican University Mathematical Olympiad
2022	Honorable Mention at the International Mathematics Competition for University Students
2021	Bronze Medal at the International Mathematics Competition for University Students
2021	Gold Medal at the Caribbean Finals of the International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)
2020	Bronze Medal at the Caribbean Finals of the International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)
2018	Bronze Medal at the Iberoamerican Mathematics Olympiad
2017	Honorable Mention at the International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)
2016	Honorable Mention at the Central American and Caribbean Mathematics Olympiad

Conferences & Workshops

Date	September 2024
Event	11th Heidelberg Laureate Forum
Location	Heidelberg, Germany
Date	July 2023
Event	Conference on Rings and Factorizations 2023
LOCATION	Graz, Austria
Note	I was unable to assist due to pending visa paperwork

Work Experience

Period	January 2024 — Present Day	
Employer	Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	
Job Title	Researcher and instructor	
University	University of Havana Havana, Cuba	
Period	June 2024 — September 2024	
Employer	Nethermind	
Job Title	Blockchain developer & cryptography researcher (internship)	

Marcos Tirador Curriculum Vitae

Period	February 2024 — June 2024
Employer	Divine Solutions LLC
Job Title	Fullstack developer

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Topics Position	February 2024 — Present Day Data Structures and Algorithms Instructor Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	Havana, Cuba
Topics Position	May 2024 — September 2024 Advanced Data Structures and Algorithms Instructor Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	Havana, Cuba
Topics Position	February 2024 — July 2024 Introduction to Programming with Python Instructor Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	Havana, Cuba
Topics Position	February 2022 — January 2024 Data Structures and Algorithms Student Assistant Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	Havana, Cuba
Topics	May 2019 — August 2019 Number Theory, Algebra and Combinatorics Math Instructor Cuban teams training for international competitions	Havana, Cuba

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, C#, JavaScript, C, C++, Haskell, Prolog, R, Solidity (with a higher level of expertise in the first two).

Others: .NET Core, ASP.NET, Node.js, React, MySQL, Keras, Ethereum.